const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"Infections caused by which organisms are treated with pyrantel pamoate?","answers":[{"option":"Clonorchis sinensis and Trichuris trichuria","bool":false},{"option":"Enterobius vermicularis and Ascaris lumbricoides","bool":true},{"option":"Taenia solium and Echinococcus granulosus","bool":false},{"option":"Trichinella spiralis and Strongyloides stercoralis","bool":false},{"option":"Diphyllobothrium latum and Wucheria bancrofti","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"The Pakistan Medical and Dental Council found a medical practitioner involved in dichotomy. He is guilty of which of the following kind of offense?","answers":[{"option":"Perjury","bool":false},{"option":"Civil malpraxix","bool":false},{"option":"Criminal negligence","bool":false},{"option":"Professional misconduct","bool":true},{"option":"Contributory negligence","bool":false}]},{"id":2,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"For which of these organisms is pyrantel pamoate not effective?","answers":[{"option":"Pinworm","bool":false},{"option":"Whipworm","bool":true},{"option":"Roundworm","bool":false},{"option":"Hookworm","bool":false},{"option":"All nematodes","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"Which of these drugs is useful for the prevention of retrograde intestinal cysticercosis?","answers":[{"option":"Ketoconazole","bool":false},{"option":"Niclosamide","bool":false},{"option":"Praziquantel","bool":true},{"option":"Steroids","bool":false},{"option":"Albendazole","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"Which of these drugs is used to treat the exoerythrocytic stage of malarial parasite?","answers":[{"option":"Primaquine","bool":true},{"option":"Quinine","bool":false},{"option":"Artemether","bool":false},{"option":"Chloroquinine","bool":false},{"option":"Dapsone","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"For which of the following disorders is chloroquine used as an anti-inflammatory drug?","answers":[{"option":"Rheumatoid arthritis","bool":true},{"option":"Intestinal amebiasis","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatic amebiasis","bool":false},{"option":"Malaria","bool":false},{"option":"Babesiosis","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"What is the most common side effect of penicillin?","answers":[{"option":"Nephrotoxicity","bool":false},{"option":"Ototoxicity","bool":false},{"option":"Paraeshtesias","bool":false},{"option":"Hypersensitivity reactions","bool":true},{"option":"Rhabdomyolysis","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"Which of these drugs is penicillinase-resistant?","answers":[{"option":"Methicillin","bool":true},{"option":"Ampicillin","bool":false},{"option":"Penicillin V","bool":false},{"option":"Penicillin G","bool":false},{"option":"Amoxicillin","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"Which of these methods is not useful in the management of Clostridium difficile infections?","answers":[{"option":"Metronidazole","bool":false},{"option":"Isolation of the patient","bool":false},{"option":"IV vancomycin","bool":true},{"option":"Removal of offending agent","bool":false},{"option":"Immunoglobulins","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"A 21-year-old male is being treated for malaria with quinine, following which he experiences a blackish discoloration of his urine. What is this complication called?","answers":[{"option":"Alkaptonuria","bool":false},{"option":"Blackwater fever","bool":true},{"option":"Aplastic anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Rhabdomyolysis","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral malaria","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"What is the meaning of the term 'Voire dire'?","answers":[{"option":"To confess murder","bool":false},{"option":"To take judgement","bool":false},{"option":"To accuse someone","bool":false},{"option":"To claim mental illness","bool":false},{"option":"To take oath","bool":true},{"option":"To pass judgment","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"A 7-year-old girl presents to the office with a complaint of fever for the last 10 days. She also developed a red, spotty rash over her abdomen 2 days ago. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Cholera","bool":false},{"option":"Pancreatitis","bool":false},{"option":"Tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Drug reaction","bool":false},{"option":"Enteric fever","bool":true}]},{"id":12,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"What is the best test for the diagnosis of enteric fever?","answers":[{"option":"Clinical","bool":false},{"option":"PCR assay","bool":false},{"option":"Throat swab","bool":false},{"option":"Blood culture","bool":true},{"option":"Stool culture","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"In which of the following courts does failure to respond to summons lead to punishment?","answers":[{"option":"Supreme court","bool":false},{"option":"High court","bool":false},{"option":"All courts","bool":true},{"option":"Civil court","bool":false},{"option":"Lower court","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"What are 'leading' questions?","answers":[{"option":"An open-ended question","bool":false},{"option":"The last question","bool":false},{"option":"A question which is relevant to the case","bool":false},{"option":"A question which directly or indirectly suggests its own answer","bool":true},{"option":"A question which follows an opening question","bool":false}]},{"id":15,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"What does 'Risos sardonicus' refer to?","answers":[{"option":"Established tetanus","bool":true},{"option":"Myasthenia gravis","bool":false},{"option":"Lockjaw","bool":false},{"option":"Botulism","bool":false},{"option":"Tetany","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"Which of these diseases is characterized by the presence of 'Negri bodies'?","answers":[{"option":"Rubella","bool":false},{"option":"Rabies","bool":true},{"option":"Chickenpox","bool":false},{"option":"Mumps","bool":false},{"option":"Measles","bool":false}]},{"id":17,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"A 19-year-old man presents with right hypochondrial pain and fever for the last 5 days. He also mentions having a few episodes of bloody diarrhea one month ago. What is the most conclusive step in establishing the diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Complete blood count","bool":false},{"option":"Serum antibodies","bool":true},{"option":"Abdominal CT scan","bool":false},{"option":"Liver function tests","bool":false},{"option":"Stool O&P","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"Which of these drugs is not a nucleotide reverse transcriptase inhibitor?","answers":[{"option":"Delavirdine","bool":true},{"option":"Abacavir","bool":false},{"option":"Stavudine","bool":false},{"option":"Didanosine","bool":false},{"option":"Zidovudine","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"Intake of which of the following drugs causes a Mazzotti-like reaction?","answers":[{"option":"Ivermectin","bool":true},{"option":"Niclosamide","bool":false},{"option":"Praziquantel","bool":false},{"option":"Pyrantel pamoate","bool":false},{"option":"Albendazole","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"Which of the following drugs is used in the treatment of filariasis?","answers":[{"option":"Diethylcarbamazine","bool":true},{"option":"Ivermectin","bool":false},{"option":"Praziquantel","bool":false},{"option":"Niclosamide","bool":false},{"option":"Albendazole","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"Which of the following drugs acts on the nicotinic receptor?","answers":[{"option":"Ivermectin","bool":false},{"option":"Piperazine","bool":true},{"option":"Albendazole","bool":false},{"option":"Mebendazole","bool":false},{"option":"Diethylcarbamazine","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"Which of the following drugs is given in Wuchereria bancrofti?","answers":[{"option":"Diethylcarbamazine","bool":true},{"option":"Praziquantel","bool":false},{"option":"Pyrantel pamoate","bool":false},{"option":"Niclosamide","bool":false},{"option":"Albendazole","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"Which of the following is graze is synonymous to?","answers":[{"option":"Cut","bool":false},{"option":"Contact abrasion","bool":false},{"option":"Friction burn","bool":true},{"option":"Scratch","bool":false},{"option":"Laceration","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"What is the timeframe between the vaccine and booster dose for an injectable typhoid vaccine?","answers":[{"option":"5 years","bool":false},{"option":"3 years","bool":false},{"option":"2 years","bool":true},{"option":"6 years","bool":false},{"option":"4 years","bool":false}]},{"id":25,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"A 7-year-old child has had 6 to 8 small volume stools daily for the last 3 days. The stools do not contain any blood or mucus. On examination, no signs of dehydration are noticed. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Campylobacter infection","bool":false},{"option":"Shigellosis","bool":false},{"option":"Enterohemorrhagic Escherichia coli","bool":false},{"option":"Cholera","bool":true},{"option":"Amebiasis","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"What is the most common pulmonary disorder in an AIDS patient?","answers":[{"option":"Pneumocystis infection","bool":false},{"option":"Lung cancer","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary abscess","bool":false},{"option":"Tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Bacterial pneumonia","bool":true}]},{"id":27,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"What is the mode of action of dapsone?","answers":[{"option":"Inhibition of bacterial transcription","bool":false},{"option":"Lysis of bacterial cell walls","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibition of bacterial protein synthesis","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibition of bacterial folate synthesis","bool":true},{"option":"Inhibition of bacterial topoisomerases","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"A 31-year-old female presents with a painless skin rash behind her right ear. On examination, it is a patch-like hypopigmented area with reduced sensation and well-demarcated borders. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Squamous cell carcinoma of the skin","bool":false},{"option":"Tuberculoid leprosy","bool":true},{"option":"Skin burn","bool":false},{"option":"Neurofibromatosis","bool":false},{"option":"Lepromatous leprosy","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"Which type of immunity is observed in tuberculoid leprosy?","answers":[{"option":"Natural immunity","bool":false},{"option":"Humoral immunity","bool":false},{"option":"Passive immunity","bool":false},{"option":"Skin barrier","bool":false},{"option":"Cell mediated immunity","bool":true}]},{"id":30,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"What is the route of administration for the measles vaccine?","answers":[{"option":"Oral","bool":false},{"option":"Subcutaneous","bool":true},{"option":"Sublingual","bool":false},{"option":"Intravenous","bool":false},{"option":"Intramuscular","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"In which of the following forms of asphyxia are Tardieu spots not seen?","answers":[{"option":"Drowning","bool":true},{"option":"Choking","bool":false},{"option":"Throttling","bool":false},{"option":"Hanging","bool":false},{"option":"Smothering","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"Which organism is responsible for leprosy?","answers":[{"option":"Mycobacterium avium","bool":false},{"option":"Mycobacterium tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Mycobacterium leprae","bool":true},{"option":"Mycobacterium bovis","bool":false},{"option":"Mycobacterium intracellulare","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"How many serotypes of dengue virus exist?","answers":[{"option":"2","bool":false},{"option":"1","bool":false},{"option":"4","bool":true},{"option":"10","bool":false},{"option":"8","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"What is the mode of transmission for dengue virus?","answers":[{"option":"Feco-oral","bool":false},{"option":"Droplet","bool":false},{"option":"Vector","bool":true},{"option":"Contact","bool":false},{"option":"Airborne","bool":false}]},{"id":35,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"A 40-year-old farmer is brought to the emergency after collapsing in his home. After regaining consciousness, he complains of right hypochondrial pain and on imaging, calcified cysts are observed in his liver. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Pyogenic liver abscess","bool":false},{"option":"Liver cancer","bool":false},{"option":"Colorectal metastases","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatic amebiasis","bool":false},{"option":"Hydatid cyst","bool":true}]},{"id":36,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"What is the best confirmatory test for hydatid cyst disease?","answers":[{"option":"Cysts on ultrasound","bool":false},{"option":"Positive serology for the organism","bool":false},{"option":"Daughter cysts on CT scan","bool":true},{"option":"Calcifications on X-ray","bool":false},{"option":"Daughter cysts on ultrasound","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"Which of the following statements regarding primary HIV is incorrect?","answers":[{"option":"Fever with rash is one of the clinical features","bool":false},{"option":"Usually manifests 3 months after exposure","bool":true},{"option":"70-80 percent of cases are symptomatic","bool":false},{"option":"Fall in CD4 count to 300-400/mm3","bool":false},{"option":"High viral RNA loads are detected","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"What is the route of administration of enfuvirtide?","answers":[{"option":"Intravenous","bool":false},{"option":"Oral","bool":false},{"option":"Subcutaneous","bool":true},{"option":"Intramuscular","bool":false},{"option":"Dermal","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"Which drug acts by inhibiting ADP phosphorylation?","answers":[{"option":"Albendazole","bool":false},{"option":"Praziquantel","bool":false},{"option":"Diethylcarbamazine","bool":false},{"option":"Niclosamide","bool":true},{"option":"lvermectin","bool":false}]},{"id":40,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"What is thanatology?","answers":[{"option":"Study of food chemistry","bool":false},{"option":"Study of jail architecture","bool":false},{"option":"Study of the phenomena of death","bool":true},{"option":"Study of plants","bool":false},{"option":"Study of life","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"Which of the following causes typhoid fever?","answers":[{"option":"Salmonella typhi","bool":true},{"option":"Shigella","bool":false},{"option":"Rickettsia typhi","bool":false},{"option":"Rickettsia prowazekii","bool":false},{"option":"Escherichia coli","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"What is the maximum fine that can be set by a 1st class magistrate?","answers":[{"option":"100 Rs","bool":false},{"option":"5,000 Rs","bool":false},{"option":"1,50,000 Rs","bool":false},{"option":"1,000 Rs","bool":false},{"option":"15,000 Rs","bool":true}]},{"id":43,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"Which of the following is not a mode of transmission of HIV?","answers":[{"option":"Blood transfer","bool":false},{"option":"Maternal-fetal transmission","bool":false},{"option":"Sexual transmission","bool":false},{"option":"Needle sharing","bool":false},{"option":"Insect transmission","bool":true}]},{"id":44,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"What causes shingles?","answers":[{"option":"Human herpesvirus 8","bool":false},{"option":"Epstein–Barr virus","bool":false},{"option":"Varicella-zoster virus","bool":true},{"option":"Herpes simplex virus type 1","bool":false},{"option":"Cytomegalovirus","bool":false}]},{"id":45,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"How many trophozoites arise during the excystation of Giardia lamblia?","answers":[{"option":"1","bool":false},{"option":"2","bool":true},{"option":"3","bool":false},{"option":"4","bool":false},{"option":"5","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"Which of the following is a proinflammatory mediator?","answers":[{"option":"IL-1","bool":true},{"option":"Corticosteroids","bool":false},{"option":"TH2 cytokines","bool":false},{"option":"IL-10","bool":false},{"option":"TGF-β","bool":false}]},{"id":47,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"What is the duration of treatment for leprosy?","answers":[{"option":"2 months","bool":false},{"option":"36 months","bool":false},{"option":"12 months","bool":true},{"option":"2 weeks","bool":false},{"option":"2 days","bool":false}]},{"id":48,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"What does the respiratory burst in acute inflammation help in?","answers":[{"option":"Increase breathing rate","bool":false},{"option":"Generate H₂O","bool":false},{"option":"Decrease breathing rate","bool":false},{"option":"Produce reactive oxygen species","bool":true},{"option":"Protect DNA","bool":false}]},{"id":49,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"Which of the following is released by dead bacteria that can cause symptoms?","answers":[{"option":"Endotoxins","bool":true},{"option":"Virions","bool":false},{"option":"Exotoxins","bool":false},{"option":"Electrolytes","bool":false},{"option":"Mitochondrial enzymes","bool":false}]},{"id":50,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"What are p17, p24, and p55 in HIV?","answers":[{"option":"Phospholipids","bool":false},{"option":"Sulfatides","bool":false},{"option":"Glycoproteins","bool":true},{"option":"Lipids","bool":false},{"option":"Cyclins","bool":false}]},{"id":51,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"Which one of these is not a feature of tetanus?","answers":[{"option":"Dysphagia","bool":false},{"option":"Altered mental status","bool":true},{"option":"Board like abdomen","bool":false},{"option":"Opisthotonus","bool":false},{"option":"Risus sardonicus","bool":false}]},{"id":52,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"What form of plasmodium parasite is taken in by the mosquitoes when they bite humans?","answers":[{"option":"Gametocytes","bool":true},{"option":"Sporozoites","bool":false},{"option":"Ameboid form","bool":false},{"option":"Merozoites","bool":false},{"option":"Schizont","bool":false}]},{"id":53,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"What is the chemical makeup of the tetanus toxin?","answers":[{"option":"Peptide","bool":true},{"option":"Carbohydrate","bool":false},{"option":"Exotoxin","bool":false},{"option":"Multigenic","bool":false},{"option":"Endotoxin","bool":false}]},{"id":54,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"What is the antibiotic of choice for established tetanus?","answers":[{"option":"Vancomycin","bool":false},{"option":"Levofloxacin","bool":false},{"option":"Sulfamethoxazole","bool":false},{"option":"Penicillin G","bool":true},{"option":"Ceftriaxone","bool":false}]},{"id":55,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"What is the confirmatory test for HIV?","answers":[{"option":"T-lymphocyte subset assay","bool":false},{"option":"ELISA","bool":false},{"option":"Rapid test","bool":false},{"option":"Western blot","bool":true},{"option":"Simple test","bool":false}]},{"id":56,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"What is the vector for the spread of dengue fever?","answers":[{"option":"Anopheles mosquito","bool":false},{"option":"Deer fly","bool":false},{"option":"Tsetse fly","bool":false},{"option":"Aedes mosquito","bool":true},{"option":"Dermacentor tick","bool":false}]},{"id":57,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"What is the earliest sign of tetanus?","answers":[{"option":"Opisthotonus","bool":false},{"option":"Board like abdominal wall","bool":false},{"option":"Risus sardonicus","bool":false},{"option":"Violent spasms","bool":false},{"option":"Lockjaw","bool":true}]},{"id":58,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"What is the vector for the spread of malaria?","answers":[{"option":"Deer fly","bool":false},{"option":"Aedes mosquito","bool":false},{"option":"Anopheles mosquito","bool":true},{"option":"Tsetse fly","bool":false},{"option":"Dermacentor tick","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"What is the percentage positivity in hydatid cyst disease serology?","answers":[{"option":"20%","bool":false},{"option":"100%","bool":false},{"option":"5-10%","bool":false},{"option":"70%","bool":false},{"option":"80%","bool":true}]},{"id":60,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"What is the mode of transmission of trichinosis?","answers":[{"option":"Eating undercooked meat","bool":true},{"option":"Drinking contaminated water","bool":false},{"option":"Walking barefoot on sand","bool":false},{"option":"Mosquito bite","bool":false},{"option":"Eating food contaminated with fecal material","bool":false}]},{"id":61,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"Which of these cephalosporins is 4th generation?","answers":[{"option":"Ceftriaxone","bool":false},{"option":"Cefazolin","bool":false},{"option":"Cefoxitin","bool":false},{"option":"Ceftazidime","bool":false},{"option":"Cefepime","bool":true}]},{"id":62,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"Which one of these is a diagnostic feature of Echinococcal infection?","answers":[{"option":"Skin rash","bool":false},{"option":"Cystic spaces in the brain","bool":false},{"option":"Brood capsules","bool":true},{"option":"Bloody diarrhea","bool":false},{"option":"Flask-shaped colonic ulcer","bool":false}]},{"id":63,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"Which of these organisms contain 'endotoxin'?","answers":[{"option":"Protozoa","bool":false},{"option":"Gram negative bacteria","bool":true},{"option":"Viruses","bool":false},{"option":"Acid fast bacteria","bool":false},{"option":"Gram positive bacteria","bool":false}]},{"id":64,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"Which type of vaccine is used for chickenpox?","answers":[{"option":"Killed vaccine","bool":false},{"option":"Subunit vaccine","bool":false},{"option":"Toxoid vaccine","bool":false},{"option":"Inactivated vaccine","bool":false},{"option":"Live attenuated vaccine","bool":true}]},{"id":65,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"How would a western blot test be deemed positive?","answers":[{"option":"Minimum 7 bands present","bool":false},{"option":"Minimum 2 bands present","bool":false},{"option":"Minimum 3 bands present","bool":true},{"option":"No bands present","bool":false},{"option":"Maximum 2 bands present","bool":false}]},{"id":66,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"Which drug that is used to treat leparomatous leprosy also has an anti-inflammatory effect?","answers":[{"option":"Ofloxacin","bool":false},{"option":"Tetracycline","bool":false},{"option":"Clofazimine","bool":true},{"option":"Dapsone","bool":false},{"option":"Minocycline","bool":false}]},{"id":67,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"Which arachidonic acid metabolite is mainly responsible for leukocyte adhesion?","answers":[{"option":"Prostacyclin","bool":false},{"option":"Leukotriene B4","bool":true},{"option":"Leukotriene D4","bool":false},{"option":"Leukotriene C4","bool":false},{"option":"Leukotriene E4","bool":false}]},{"id":68,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"Which of the following courts can give a death sentence?","answers":[{"option":"Section 30 magistrate","bool":false},{"option":"3rd class magistrate","bool":false},{"option":"1st class magistrate","bool":false},{"option":"2nd class magistrate","bool":false},{"option":"Sessions court","bool":true}]},{"id":69,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"What is a dying declaration?","answers":[{"option":"A person's statement made just before his death, relating to the cause of death","bool":true},{"option":"An observation of certain facts from which an inference can be concluded","bool":false},{"option":"A statement taken on oath before magistrate in the presence of the accused and his lawyer","bool":false},{"option":"A document produced for the inspection of court","bool":false},{"option":"A statement on oath made by a witness in a judicial proceeding","bool":false}]},{"id":70,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"What is a dying deposition?","answers":[{"option":"An observation of certain facts from which an inference can be concluded","bool":false},{"option":"A statement on oath made by a witness in a judicial proceeding","bool":false},{"option":"A person's statement made just before his death, relating to the cause of death","bool":false},{"option":"A document produced for the inspection of court","bool":false},{"option":"A statement taken on oath before magistrate in the presence of the accused and his lawyer","bool":true}]},{"id":71,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"How is leprosy transmitted?","answers":[{"option":"Airborne droplets","bool":false},{"option":"Vector transmission","bool":false},{"option":"Genetically","bool":false},{"option":"Transplacentally","bool":false},{"option":"Contact with nasal secretions","bool":true}]},{"id":72,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"In which of the following conditions are nerves thickened?","answers":[{"option":"Rabies","bool":false},{"option":"Tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Dysentery","bool":false},{"option":"Tuberculoid leprosy","bool":true},{"option":"Lepromatous leprosy","bool":false}]},{"id":73,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"What is a hostile witness?","answers":[{"option":"A well qualified and trained witness that can draw conclusions from facts observed by him and others","bool":false},{"option":"A witness who turned hostile against the party that called him, making statements contradictory to facts","bool":true},{"option":"A witness who could not show up to court","bool":false},{"option":"A witness with a background in martial arts","bool":false},{"option":"A witness who can testify only the facts observed by him","bool":false}]},{"id":74,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"Which of the following is not present in granulomas?","answers":[{"option":"Lymphocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Fibroblasts","bool":false},{"option":"Epithelial cells","bool":true},{"option":"Langhans giant cells","bool":false},{"option":"Caseation","bool":false}]},{"id":75,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"Which of the following is not present in oral rehydration therapy (ORS)?","answers":[{"option":"Glucose","bool":false},{"option":"Sodium","bool":false},{"option":"Albumin","bool":true},{"option":"Potassium","bool":false},{"option":"Water","bool":false}]},{"id":76,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"Where does the ookinete of the malarial parasite grow?","answers":[{"option":"Brain","bool":false},{"option":"Erythrocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Mosquito stomach","bool":false},{"option":"Midgut wall","bool":true},{"option":"Liver","bool":false}]},{"id":77,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"Clostridium difficile is associated with which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Constipation","bool":false},{"option":"Erythema nodosum","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudomembranous colitis","bool":true},{"option":"Brain abscesses","bool":false}]},{"id":78,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"What is the external incubation period for dengue?","answers":[{"option":"1 month","bool":false},{"option":"10 days","bool":true},{"option":"3 weeks","bool":false},{"option":"2 days","bool":false},{"option":"5 hours","bool":false}]},{"id":79,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"Systemic inflammatory response syndrome (SIRS) is associated with which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Decreased respiratory rate","bool":false},{"option":">10% band forms","bool":true},{"option":"4,000 > WBC > 12,000 cells/mm3","bool":false},{"option":"Temperatue 37°C","bool":false},{"option":"Bradycardia","bool":false}]},{"id":80,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"Which of the following is true regarding leprosy?","answers":[{"option":"Bacilli are seen in hypersensitivity reaction","bool":false},{"option":"Bacilli are seen in brain nuclei","bool":false},{"option":"Bacilli are seen in tuberculoid reaction","bool":false},{"option":"Bacilli are seen in gut","bool":false},{"option":"Bacilli are seen in skin allergy reaction","bool":true}]},{"id":81,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"Where are organisms of cutaneous Leishmaniasis seen?","answers":[{"option":"Area of bite of sandfly","bool":true},{"option":"Skin of palms","bool":false},{"option":"Area close to sandfly bite","bool":false},{"option":"Lymph nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Skin of soles","bool":false}]},{"id":82,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"What would the blood smear of a patient with malaria show?","answers":[{"option":"Square bodies","bool":false},{"option":"Crescent shaped bodies","bool":true},{"option":"Granular bodies","bool":false},{"option":"Bilobar bodies","bool":false},{"option":"Multilobar bodies","bool":false}]},{"id":83,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"What is dysentery?","answers":[{"option":"Mucous lined stool","bool":false},{"option":"Bleeding per-rectal only","bool":false},{"option":"Occult blood in stool","bool":false},{"option":"Visibly bloody stool","bool":true},{"option":"Watery stool","bool":false}]},{"id":84,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"What is the incubation period for leprosy?","answers":[{"option":"Few years","bool":true},{"option":"Few weeks","bool":false},{"option":"Few hours","bool":false},{"option":"Few days","bool":false},{"option":"Few months","bool":false}]},{"id":85,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"What is the mechanism of action of Vibrio cholerae?","answers":[{"option":"Actin polymerization","bool":false},{"option":"Gal-gal pili bind to bladder mucosa","bool":false},{"option":"Ferments lactose","bool":false},{"option":"Produce protease","bool":false},{"option":"ADP ribosylation of Gs protein","bool":true}]},{"id":86,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"Which of the following is praziquantel ineffective against?","answers":[{"option":"Trematodes","bool":false},{"option":"Clonorchis sinensis","bool":false},{"option":"Nematodes","bool":true},{"option":"Blood flukes","bool":false},{"option":"Paragonimus westermani","bool":false}]},{"id":87,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"Which of the following is the drug of choice for onchocerciasis?","answers":[{"option":"Bithional","bool":false},{"option":"Niclosamide","bool":false},{"option":"Praziquantel","bool":false},{"option":"Triclabendazole","bool":false},{"option":"Ivermectin","bool":true}]},{"id":88,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"Which of the following is the drug of choice for filariasis?","answers":[{"option":"Praziquantel","bool":false},{"option":"Bithional","bool":false},{"option":"Niclosamide","bool":false},{"option":"Triclabendazole","bool":false},{"option":"Diethylcarbamazine","bool":true}]},{"id":89,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"Which of the following courts can grant an amnesty of the death sentence?","answers":[{"option":"2nd class magistrate","bool":false},{"option":"High court","bool":true},{"option":"Sessions court","bool":false},{"option":"1st class magistrate","bool":false},{"option":"3rd class magistrate","bool":false}]},{"id":90,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"Which of the following is the earliest clinical symptom of tetanus?","answers":[{"option":"Opisthotonos","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory distress","bool":false},{"option":"Uncontrolled urination","bool":false},{"option":"Neck stiffness","bool":false},{"option":"Lockjaw","bool":true}]},{"id":91,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"Which cells secrete histamine during acute inflammation?","answers":[{"option":"B-lymphocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Macrophages","bool":false},{"option":"Mast cells","bool":true},{"option":"Fibroblasts","bool":false},{"option":"T-lymphocytes","bool":false}]},{"id":92,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"What intravenous drugs should be given as the first choice, following fluid resuscitation, in sepsis?","answers":[{"option":"Adrenaline","bool":false},{"option":"Vasopressin","bool":false},{"option":"Dobutamine","bool":false},{"option":"Dopamine","bool":false},{"option":"Noradrenaline","bool":true}]},{"id":93,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"Which of these cells are affected by HIV in the intestinal mucosa?","answers":[{"option":"B cells","bool":false},{"option":"Kupffer cells","bool":false},{"option":"Dust cells","bool":false},{"option":"Neutrophils","bool":false},{"option":"Macrophages","bool":true}]},{"id":94,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"Which vaccines are given at birth according to the EPI schedule?","answers":[{"option":"Pneumo + BCG","bool":false},{"option":"BCG + OPV 1","bool":false},{"option":"Penta + OPV","bool":false},{"option":"OPV + BCG + hep B","bool":true},{"option":"OPV 0 + BCG","bool":false}]},{"id":95,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"Which antibodies are formed in syphilis?","answers":[{"option":"Anti nuclear antibodies","bool":false},{"option":"Reagin","bool":true},{"option":"Anti Smith antibodies","bool":false},{"option":"Anti dsDNA antibodies","bool":false},{"option":"Anti mitochondrial antibodies","bool":false}]},{"id":96,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"Which inotropic agent is given in cardiogenic shock?","answers":[{"option":"Dopamine","bool":false},{"option":"Dobutamine","bool":true},{"option":"Epinephrine","bool":false},{"option":"Norepinephrine","bool":false},{"option":"Phenoxybenzamine","bool":false}]},{"id":97,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"What is the movement of leukocytes towards an infected tissue called?","answers":[{"option":"Chemotaxis","bool":true},{"option":"Opsonization","bool":false},{"option":"Migration","bool":false},{"option":"Tumbling motility","bool":false},{"option":"Phagocytosis","bool":false}]},{"id":98,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"How long does it take for antibodies to appear after HIV infection?","answers":[{"option":"30 days","bool":false},{"option":"6 days","bool":false},{"option":"3 days","bool":false},{"option":"60-90 days","bool":false},{"option":"10-14 days","bool":true}]},{"id":99,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"Which of these is not an indication for antiviral therapy for chickenpox infections?","answers":[{"option":"Uncomplicated chickenpox in children","bool":true},{"option":"Chickenpox in immunocompromised patients regardless of duration","bool":false},{"option":"Chickenpox in pregnant women regardless of duration","bool":false},{"option":"Complicated chickenpox regardless of duration","bool":false},{"option":"Uncomplicated chickenpox presenting within 24-48 hours","bool":false}]},{"id":100,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2017","question":"A diabetic woman came to the clinic with the complaint of vaginal itch. Which of the following is the most likely cause of her condition?","answers":[{"option":"Human papilloma virus","bool":false},{"option":"Fungal infection","bool":true},{"option":"Bacterial infection","bool":false},{"option":"Chlamydia","bool":false},{"option":"Eczema","bool":false}]}]
export default arr